Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we
have a lesson for you all about school.
That's right, today we're going to
take a look at a child's report card.
So we're going to talk a little
bit about what this means, what
is a report card and also
everything that's inside this report.
That's right, so we're going to learn
how to describe a child's schoolwork.
Is it good?
Is it bad?
So listen to our dialogue and we'll be back
in a minute to discuss the meaning of some
of these words and phrases.
Look, Jimmy's report card came today.
Let's have a look.
What is this?
We're all the grades.
He's in the third grade, Sam.
You see, under each
subject that he's being taught
in school, he receives a
mark from one to three.
A one means his achievement
or work is excellence.
Here in science, for example, he got
a two, which means it's satisfactory.
What about here in physical education?
He got a three here, which
means it's unsatisfactory.
We should work on that with him.
So confusing.
In my day, we got
an A or a B, if we were
doing well, and if we failed
an exam, we would get an F.
All right, we're back.
So now let's start with
some language takeaway.
All right, the first phrase here we have
in language takeaway is actually a thing.
It's the report card, and this
is the topic of today's dialogue.
That's right.
Now you may remember, I'm sure pretty
much it's standard everywhere in the world.
You get a report, a
small little report that
tells your parents how well or
how poorly you are doing in school.
That's right.
Or maybe two or three
months, your teacher will
write down how she or he thinks
that you're performing at school.
Usually parents have to sign this.
They have to say, okay, I see
that my child is doing well or
that he's doing poorly and
then the teacher will know as well.
And I think, well, you
get report cards in
elementary school in high
school and also in university, right?
You do get a report card of some sort.
That's right.
In university in America,
we call them grades,
we don't really call
them a report card.
In high school, middle
school, and elementary
school, so before college, we
actually have a piece of paper.
And that's why it's called a card.
Yeah, that's right.
I think now for universities, especially
you just go online and you see your grades.
That's right.
It's on the internet.
But the important
thing about the report
card is that it tells a parent and a
student what his or her grades are.
That's right.
grades, this is a noun,
is basically your score.
That's right.
So maybe you took a test and
you did a very well on your test
and you had some homework and
you did very well on your homework.
So you have a good grade.
That's right.
But if you don't do your
homework and you don't
do well on your test,
you have a bad grade.
That's right.
So for example, like in the
United States, it's over 100 points.
So maybe a good grade
would be 95 points out of 100.
So we call that an A.
That's called an A.
That's right.
If you have a bad grade, maybe
that's an F, which is 20% or 30%.
Right.
Okay.
So now this is where
we need to make a
difference between the
grades that his father was
looking for and then the mom
says he's in the third grade.
So it's very different
between having good
grades or bad grades and
fifth grade or third grade.
All right.
Two different grades.
And we know this is confusing.
I want to explain a little bit.
Third grade is actually the
third year of elementary school.
That's right.
So in the American
education system, we start
in kindergarten and we
have first grade, second
grade, third grade, all the way up
until the end, which is 12th grade.
That's right.
So that's everything
between when you're
five years old and
when you're 18 years old.
And each year at
school is a grade, a level.
That's right.
So as you said, it's a grade in
different parts of the country.
I'm not really sure if they call them a
grades or they have these, the same system.
But basically, that's
what it means in English.
You have first grade, third grade,
12th grade, finally when you graduate.
That's right.
So you can say, my son is in eighth
grade, he's in his eighth year of school.
Right.
Very good.
So that is the difference and now we're
going to take a look at something that has
to do with grades as
well is the marks that
you get in your test
or in your report card.
Right.
So this might actually help.
Remember when we said on your report card,
your teacher might write down your grade.
That means do you have an A or a B or a C.
Well, another way to call this is a mark.
So he has good marks.
He has good grades.
So they're basically the
same thing grades and marks.
That's right.
They are.
And I know that in Britain, I think
people more commonly say marks.
She got terrible marks at school
and her father was angry with her.
Okay.
But in America, we often say, you know, if
you get good grades, I'll buy you sweets.
That's right.
Okay.
So you get a prize if you get good grades.
Usually.
Well, it depends on your parents.
That's right.
Now, as we said, you
can have a grade that's
usually a number or
a letter like ABCD F.
But you can also get marks that
are just very much black or white.
It's satisfactory or
unsatisfactory like in this case.
That's right.
This is an adjective.
It describes something is a good thing.
So how did he do?
Well, his performance was satisfactory.
It's okay.
But if it's bad or if it's not
good, we call it unsatisfactory.
That's right.
So this doesn't really have
a number, as you can tell.
It's just basically pass or fail.
That's about it.
Good or bad?
That's exactly.
And we'll explain this in a minute.
There's some classes where
you can't have a grade like an A or
a B. And that's why we have
this satisfactory unsatisfactory.
That's right.
All right.
So we've taken a look
at a lot of language there.
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again?
Look, Jimmy's report card came today.
Let's have a look.
What is this?
We're all the grades.
He's in the third grade, Sam.
You see, under each
subject that he's being
taught in school, he receives
a mark from one to three.
A one means his achievement
or work as excellence.
Here in science, for example, he got
a two, which means it's satisfactory.
What about here in physical education?
He got a three here, which
means it's unsatisfactory.
We should work on that with him.
So confusing.
In my day, we got an A or
a B if we were doing well.
And if we failed an
exam, we would get an F.
All right.
We're back.
So now let's take a look at
some phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
You could have said,
let's have a look, Marco.
That's one of the key
phrases in today's dialogue.
That's right.
The dad got the report
carding said, all right.
Let's have a look.
All right.
This is a very common way to
say, let's see or let me look at that.
So let's have a look.
See, it's just one person
me, but we still say this, let us.
So it's plural.
It's very weird, but it just
means let me look, let me see.
And exactly.
As you said, even
though it's in plural and
you may be by yourself
or only you are going
to look at something, people
still say, let's have a look.
Let's have a look here.
Yeah.
It means I want to look at this.
So if I say, hey, I
just bought this new
CD, okay, I can say,
hey, let's have a look.
All right.
Give it to Marco and he can look at
the case and see who the musician is.
That's right.
All right.
Now talking about
one of the subjects in
school, that means
some of the classes that
you have, we had
science, we have history.
And there's another one
called physical education.
All right.
So this is a class that
has many different names.
It's physical.
So you know that it
has to do with your body.
So basically it's sports
class and you play sports
like football, basketball,
things like that.
It's a school called
PE, PE for short, yeah.
Because remember, physical in
English starts with a pH, physical.
But this is what I was
saying earlier Marco,
you can't give a person an
A or a B in physical education.
Well, you don't really.
So normally students get
satisfactory or unsatisfactory.
Right.
Because usually it doesn't mean that
you have to be very good at sports.
Sometimes it just, the effort counts.
You may not be very
good at soccer or football
or basketball, but if you try really hard,
you're running around and you're actually
doing what you're supposed to be
doing, then you get a satisfactory note.
It means, yeah, I mean,
you're not the best player in
the world, but you're doing
what you're supposed to.
Exactly.
All right.
So now when the father was
always like, oh, you know, I don't
understand this report card
in my day, we got an A or a B.
All right.
So this is a common phrase
that people say when they want to
talk about when they were children
or when they were growing up.
So older people often say, oh,
in my day, things were different.
So this is a way to make a
comparison between now and the past.
Yeah, right.
You're basically saying when I was a child
or many years ago, this was what happened
or this is how it used to be in my day,
school was much more difficult today.
That's right.
It's very, very easy.
This is how you start this comparison between
the time when you were a child to now.
Yes.
In my day.
All right.
And to finish off, we're
going to talk about
failing in exam because
obviously sometimes you do fail.
Yeah.
And if you fail, I fail
in exam, you get a
very bad grade, an F and F. So
F for fail, it's easy to remember.
That's right.
So you say, you can
say, I didn't pass the
exam, but you can also
say, I failed the exam.
And normally fail means you
received less than 60% or 50%.
So it's, yeah, 50%.
So basically you
missed if there are 10
questions on the exam, you missed
five or six or seven or all the 10 of them.
So you missed more
than half of the questions.
That's right.
And it's not only for
school, for example, your
driver's exam, when
you're going to get your
driver's license, you can
also pass or fail that exam.
And if you fail the exam,
you have to take it again.
That's right.
So that's all the fluency builder
words we have for you today.
Let's take a look at them
again, and we'll be right back.
Look, Jimmy's report card came today.
Let's have a look.
What is this?
We're all the grades.
He's in the third grade, Sam.
You see, under each
subject that he's being
taught in school, he receives
a mark from one to three.
A one means his achievement
or work is excellence.
Here in science, for example, he got
a two, which means it's satisfactory.
What about here in physical education?
He got a three here, which
means it's unsatisfactory.
We should work on that with him.
So confusing.
In my day, we got an A or
a B if we were doing well.
And if we failed an
exam, we would get an F.
All right, so big question, Marco.
When you were a student,
did you get good grades?
I got good grades, but not great grades.
I was always a type
of student that paid
attention in class, did
my homework, but never
studied.
So you did not study for the tests.
No, but that's why I never
got an A, for example, an A plus.
But I always got a B.
So I was that type of just
more chilled type of student.
You like to be in the middle.
Yeah, well, this was the thing.
I like to pay attention in class.
So that was different
because I would pay attention.
I would take some notes, but then
I would just remember everything.
So I did all right for the exam,
didn't really have to study.
But sometimes in other subjects, I did.
I really liked them.
So it wasn't studying.
It was more fun for me, so
then I would get great grades.
Oh, all right.
What about you?
Well, I always studied for tests, so
generally my grades were pretty good.
Now something that we
didn't talk about here is a GPA.
Yeah.
This is something that
is very popular in the
United States, basically,
even if you want
to apply for schools,
your GPA is with counts.
That's right.
Well, we don't really have
a GPA until high school.
And then it's in high school and college.
And GPA stands for G grade P point
A average, so grade point average.
That means we take all of our
marks, or all of our grades together.
So science grade, English grade,
history grade, and we make an average.
So if I get mostly A's, my GPA is 4.0.
If I get mostly B's, my GPA is 3.0,
and then it goes lower and lower.
And if you have a really bad GPA, like
one, you probably won't finish high school.
Now this is, the GPA
is very important for
many reasons, first
of all, because it's also
kind of a summary of your
application to universities, right?
They take a look at your GPA.
Absolutely.
So this is a way to say, okay,
how is this student overall?
How is the student in all of her classes?
That's just one class.
And then they see if you have a
3.5 to say, oh, well, it's pretty good.
Yeah, 3.5 is good, four is the best.
And again, three is good, it's okay,
but a two or one's not very good.
That's right.
So it's very interesting
because all around
the world, they have
different grading systems.
I think I would say that the United States
is the only place where I've seen that they
use the ABCDF system,
and Latin American
countries, for example,
they don't do it over 100.
They do it over 10.
So you would get a grade over
10 or in some countries over 20.
So I've seen that as well
in Italy, yeah, it's over 20.
So you would get a 14 I think
would be a passing grade over 20.
Well, let us know listeners, if you have a
different grading system in your country,
also you can let us know how were your
grades when you're studying in school.
You don't have to tell us, but
we'd like to talk to you about grades.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
Alright, we'll see you guys there.
Bye.